<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"> <id>https://jayden-lind.github.io/</id><title>Jayden Lind - Portfolio</title><subtitle>Jayden Lind - Portfolio - Homelab, Software Engineering, Security</subtitle> <updated>2023-03-26T20:59:21+11:00</updated> <author> <name>jayden-lind</name> <uri>https://jayden-lind.github.io/</uri> </author><link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://jayden-lind.github.io/feed.xml"/><link rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" href="https://jayden-lind.github.io/"/> <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator> <rights> © 2023 jayden-lind </rights> <icon>/assets/img/favicons/favicon.ico</icon> <logo>/assets/img/favicons/favicon-96x96.png</logo> <entry><title>Breaking 20 year old PC game copy protection</title><link href="https://jayden-lind.github.io/posts/taz/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Breaking 20 year old PC game copy protection" /><published>2023-03-20T00:00:00+11:00</published> <updated>2023-03-26T20:59:00+11:00</updated> <id>https://jayden-lind.github.io/posts/taz/</id> <content src="https://jayden-lind.github.io/posts/taz/" /> <author> <name>jayden-lind</name> </author> <summary> Introduction As a kid, I used to play Taz: Wanted on my PC, but nowadays it’s impossible to play these old games as most modern PCs don’t have a CD drive. While you can easily download no-CD cracks, where the CD checks have been removed, it’s more fun to create your own no-CD patch. In this post, I’ll show you how I was able to create my own no-CD patch for Taz: Wanted. CD Check After instal... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Monitoring homelab with Zabbix</title><link href="https://jayden-lind.github.io/posts/linds-zabbix/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Monitoring homelab with Zabbix" /><published>2022-11-03T00:00:00+11:00</published> <updated>2022-11-06T23:15:38+11:00</updated> <id>https://jayden-lind.github.io/posts/linds-zabbix/</id> <content src="https://jayden-lind.github.io/posts/linds-zabbix/" /> <author> <name>jayden-lind</name> </author> <summary> Introduction The best way to have visbility on what is going on in your homelab is to have monitoring over everything from Networking, Storage, and Compute hosts. To do this, I have decided to use Zabbix in HA on my Kubernetes cluster, while integrating it with my PostgreSQL HA cluster to ensure ultimate uptime of my monitoring solution. Architecture Below is a simple diagram showing the p... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Implementing Terraform with vSphere</title><link href="https://jayden-lind.github.io/posts/linds-terraform/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Implementing Terraform with vSphere" /><published>2022-10-12T00:00:00+11:00</published> <updated>2022-10-12T21:45:33+11:00</updated> <id>https://jayden-lind.github.io/posts/linds-terraform/</id> <content src="https://jayden-lind.github.io/posts/linds-terraform/" /> <author> <name>jayden-lind</name> </author> <summary> Introduction My entire homelab has been very adhoc, with VM’s in ESXi just created and then installed from a installer ISO. After working more with Kubernetes and AWS, seeing how nice it is to have easily reproducible infrastructure, and automate deployment/updates, I decided to implement Terraform into my vSphere infrastructure, and use Puppet to provision the VM’s to the way I want them. ... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Moving to Kubernetes</title><link href="https://jayden-lind.github.io/posts/linds-kubernetes/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Moving to Kubernetes" /><published>2022-07-27T00:00:00+10:00</published> <updated>2022-08-28T17:25:15+10:00</updated> <id>https://jayden-lind.github.io/posts/linds-kubernetes/</id> <content src="https://jayden-lind.github.io/posts/linds-kubernetes/" /> <author> <name>jayden-lind</name> </author> <summary> Introduction I have been running multiple Docker hosts with an assortment of containers that run random things. It was time to clean it up, define all the infrastructure, configurations, add some redundancy, and also allow easier upgrading/moving of the underlying OS. Setup Puppet Automation To automate onboarding of a VM to the kubernetes cluster, I implemented it through Puppet and my man... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>HackTheBox - Retired</title><link href="https://jayden-lind.github.io/posts/htb-retired/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="HackTheBox - Retired" /><published>2022-06-22T00:00:00+10:00</published> <updated>2023-03-23T00:06:40+11:00</updated> <id>https://jayden-lind.github.io/posts/htb-retired/</id> <content src="https://jayden-lind.github.io/posts/htb-retired/" /> <author> <name>jayden-lind</name> </author> <summary> HTB - Retired walkthrough Retired box is a medium rated difficulty box, but for me personally it was a hard box. I’ve never done any sort of binary exploitation before and because of that, this box took me a good 30+ hours to solve. I overall found this really fun, and I’m glad I did this box, as I learned a lot about binary exploitation, even if it was only a specific type. Initial Start... </summary> </entry> </feed>
